you believe the stablecoin ecosystem is broken.
What do you think is broken in an asset class that is now over 250 billion in assets has
some challenges?
Yes.
Well, I wouldn't call it broken, but definitely it's time for it to evolve.
So stablecoins now have been around for over 10 years, and it's laid the foundation for
what we know of the entire cryptocurrency ecosystem.
And more importantly it's changed how the world moves money and how a lot of companies
do business, lots of efficiencies.
However, it's time for it to evolve because there's two real challenges with the current
stablecoin 1.0 ecosystem.
One of the main challenges and a traditional complaint that we would get all of the time
is where's the backing?
Is it really collateralized?
How do we know that all the money's there?
That's one of the biggest problems.
The other one is these centralized issuers are making so much money.
The users, while they're the ones giving them all the money, they don't get to participate
in any of the upside.
So stablecoin 2.0, something that we've coined, and it's a new technology and a new, it's
the evolution of the stablecoin that we're rolling out, solves both of those issues.
So let's talk about the focus on these two items you mentioned, right?
So I think for the benefit of your audience, obviously you're the co-founder of SDBL, and
I think what you guys are trying to do there is to give back some of the yield that currently
is going in your second example to the stablecoin issuers, to the community and to users.
Can you maybe explain to us how does that work?
And also if you believe that, it will become mainstream in the coming years that the yield
of the underlying assets goes to the users of this stablecoin.
Absolutely.
Yeah, well, I'll address both of those points.
I'll start with the collateral because that one's pretty straightforward.
We know that that's been an opaque issue in the past, but now that there's this RWA narrative
and these high quality assets, such as treasuries and money market funds and other high quality
traditional assets are coming on chain, those are what's used to back stablecoins.
Those are now tokenized.
So now with stable, you can utilize these tokenized treasuries to be the collateral.
So now it's always transparent, 24/7, you're going to know exactly where the collateral
is and how much there is and that it matches the stablecoins in circulation.
So that's a really key point.
And secondly, the yield.
So people for a while have realized, okay, these centralized issues are getting all the
yield.
The first solution was a yield bearing stablecoin.
The challenge with that is it becomes a security.
So it's not freely trading.
There's a lot of friction there.
And also you have to sit on it to get that yield.
So it's really an investment.
It's not a utility.
You can't spend it.
So we've solved that.
And the way we've solved it is when you post that collateral, we meant two tokens.
We split the yield.
So the yield comes into an NFT.
It's the tokenized income stream from that treasury.
And then the principal backs USST.
So USST is our universal stablecoin, similar to USDT and USDC freely trading around the
world backed by the principal from treasuries.
But the key difference is think about the $200 plus billion that have flowed into stablecoins.
All of that yield goes to a couple centralized issuers.
Now all of that money, the people who put that in and mint the stablecoin, they're going
to get the yield.
So now the collateral is on chain.
The users get the yield.
And so yes, I definitely believe that's the future.
So it kind of democratizes the access to the yield of a lot of these stablecoins.
What you believe is the impact of the Genius Act on products like yours?
Because obviously there's a requirement that the assets have to be held in cash to cash
equivalents, but also on US treasuries.
How do you see that impacting models like yours were, the yield is separated?
Yeah, so in the US our stablecoin will be Genius Act compliant.
And that just means that you have to utilize essentially treasuries to back those specific
stablecoins, especially if you want that stablecoin to be accepted on the exchanges within the
US.
However, there will become a bifurcation because treasuries have a certain amount of
yield that are generated.
Then you can have stablecoins that are accepted the rest of the world where you can have higher
yielding instruments like credit funds and different things that may be 5% to 10% instead
of 2% to 5%.
And it's going to depend on the ecosystem that issues that stablecoin because the next
big narrative, when you think about stablecoin 1.0 it's the exchanges where all those stablecoins
moved around.
But in stablecoin 2.0, ecosystems, large companies and institutions will have their own branded
stablecoin.
And when they have their own branded stablecoin, it might not be Genius Act compliant because
they want a little more yield than just treasuries.
So we have built the technology that enables that full flexibility for ecosystems to create
their own token and brand their own currency.
You know, there's a big debate in the US as you know for Genius Act as a Genius Act explicitly
bans the token issuers from providing yield.
But obviously now there's a lot of lobbying from the banks against the crypto exchanges
to offer that yield, often the yield that is generated by lending and other methodologies.
How do you think that restriction will have an impact on what you're building but also
on the future of the stablecoin ecosystem?
I mean it's such a great point and it's so amusing to me that you know that this idea
is coming and it can't be stopped when the regulations are specifically being put in
place to stop progression, to stop the evolution.
Because the banks know how much they'll lose if people start getting yield but it's inevitable.
And our solution actually solves for that by stripping the yield and creating a distinctly
separate token so our technology platform enables full regulatory compliance.
Kind of stripping that from even from the asset itself.
You're one of the co-founders of Tether and back in the day when you look at Tether, did
you ever imagine that the stablecoin ecosystem was going to be so big so quickly?
Well I mean it's been 10 plus years so I don't know how quickly that is but however
to create a new monetary infrastructure and a new global currency that's accepted all
the way around the world and truly has transformed lives for a lot of people.
It's an honor to be part of that and you know it was always kind of in our wildest dreams
but to see how far it's come is always just tumbling, it's amazing.
But you believe there'll be, I mean you mentioned before how there'll be potentially separation
between companies that let's say they want to have in their own ecosystem their own stablecoin
but you believe there'll be one on the regulatory side as well.
I mean Tether is a very good example, they have USAT for the US market and USDT to cash
cow for let's say globally, do you believe we're going to see that separation the next
couple of years of US, non-US and potentially other jurisdictions like China and the EU
as well?
Yes I do and but what's going to take place in a few years also is they'll be clearing
houses and these stablecoins it won't matter which flavor you're using because on the
back end they'll all have an interchange and maybe a slight fee or shift to make sure that
they're fungible because what's going to happen also the next big narrative as we know is
AI and AI is going to significantly transform how transactions are done on the blockchain
because the blockchain is very complicated and it's difficult to manage all of those
things.
AI is going to do it for you so the users can talk into their wallet and say I want it
to go I want the fastest cheapest most profitable way and so AI will route that for you.
Definitely the era where finance happens behind the scenes without us realizing it that was
super interesting and that was Reeve Collins the co-founder and chairman of SDBL again
who said that stablecoins is a boring ecosystem lost going on in that space.